donaldson.com 2016-12-08

# Privacy Policy

## Your Privacy

Last modified: July 14, 2015

This Privacy Policy (or “policy”) describes the types of information Donaldson Company, Inc. (or similar terms such as “we”, “us”, or “Company”) may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the Website with a home page located at www.donaldson.com and its subordinate and affiliated pages and any page from which you navigated to this Policy, and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting and disclosing that information. Along with agreeing to our Terms of Use, and as a condition of using this Website, you agree to the collection, use, and sharing of information as described in this Privacy Policy. All terms not defined in this Privacy Policy shall have the meanings as set forth in the Terms of Use.

This policy applies to information we collect through any of the following, now or in the future:

  * On this Website.
  * In e-mail, text and other electronic messages between you and this Website.
  * Through mobile and desktop applications you download from this Website, which provide dedicated non-browser-based interaction between you and this Website.
  * When you interact with our advertising and applications on third-party websites and services, if those applications or advertising include links to this policy.

This policy does not apply to information collected by:

  * us offline or through any other means, or any third party; or 
  * any third party, including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website

This policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of this Website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates. 

**Children Under the Age of 13**

This is a business-to-business website, intended only for individuals 18 years or older. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not do any of the following on this Website:  use or provide any information, , make any purchases, use any of the interactive or public comment features ,or provide any information about yourself to us,. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at email: comm@donaldson.com or writing to Donaldson Company, Corporate Communications – MS430, PO Box 1299, Minneapolis Minnesota, 55440, U.S.A..

**Information We Collect About You and How We Collect It**

We may, now or in the future, collect several types of information from and about users of our Website, including information:

  * by which you may be personally identified and/or contacted, such as name, postal address, e-mail address, computer ID number and/or IP address, telephone number, cell/mobile phone number, fax number, social media account identifier,  social security number, or similar individually identifiable information  (collectively, " **personal information** ");
  * about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Website and usage details.

We collect this information:

  * Directly from you when you choose to provide it to us.
  * Automatically as you navigate through the site. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other similar tracking technologies.
  * From third parties, for example, our business partners.

**Information You Provide to Us  **

The information we collect on or through our Website may include:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Website. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our Website,[subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further information or services. We may also ask you for information if you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by us, and if you report a problem with our Website.
  * Records and copies of your correspondence (including e-mail addresses), if you contact us.
  * Your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of the fulfillment of your orders. You may be required to provide financial information before placing an order through our Website.
  * Your search queries on the Website.

You also may choose to provide information to be published or displayed (hereinafter, " **posted** ") on public areas of the Website, or transmitted to other users of the Website or third parties (collectively, " **User Contributions** "). Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to others at your own risk, and are considered non-confidential. We cannot control the actions of other users of the Website with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by unauthorized persons or used by others in ways to which you object.

**Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies  **

As you navigate through and interact with our Website, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns, including:

  * Details of your visits to our Website, including traffic data, location data, logs and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Website.
  * Information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system and browser type.
  * We also may use these technologies to collect information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or other online services (behavioral tracking).

The information we collect automatically may be combined with other personally identifiable information. Such information helps us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service, including by enabling us to:

  * Estimate our audience size and usage patterns.
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website according to your individual interests.
  * Speed up your searches.
  * Recognize you when you return to our Website.

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include:

  * **Cookies (or browser cookies).**  A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Website. 
  *  
  * **Flash Cookies.  **Certain features of our Website may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from and on our Website. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. 

  * **Web Beacons.**  Pages of our Website and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs. pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that permit the Company, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an e-mail and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity). 

We do not collect personal Information automatically, but we may tie this information to personal information about you that we collect from other sources or you provide to us.

**Third-party Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

Some content or applications, including advertisements, on the Website are served by third-parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers and application providers. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use our website. The information they collect may be associated with your personal information or they may collect information, including personal information, about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services . They may use this information to provide you with interest-based (behavioral) advertising or other targeted content. 

We do not control these third parties' tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible provider directly. For information about how you can opt out of receiving targeted advertising from many providers, see Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information.

**How We Use Your Information**

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

  * To communicate with you, and you explicitly and specifically consent through this writing that we, and others acting on our behalf and others with whom we are permitted to share information as described in this Privacy Policy, may send messages and communications to you through any format and through any and all communication technologies for which you have provided contact information, specifically including but not limited to email, and text message .
  * To present our Website and its contents to you, including the creation of user accounts, to permit the placement of orders, and to collect and respond to customer inquiries.
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or from others through us.
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it.
  * To process and evaluate a job application.
  * To provide you with notices about your account, orders, purchases and similar items.
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection, as well as to protect the rights or interests of third parties.
  * To notify you about changes to our Website or any products or services we offer or provide though it.
  * To keep a record of your account and other actions taken by you on the Website.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Website.
  * To combine information you provide with information from other sources.  
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information.
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

We may also use your information to contact you about our own and third-parties' goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, please see the section below on Choices, including opt-out choices.

**Disclosure of Your Information**

We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction. 

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy:

  * To our subsidiaries and affiliates.
  * To sales representatives and dealers that promote our products and services.
  * To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business, subject to certain restrictions on such third parties.
  * To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of Donaldson Company, Inc.’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by us about our Website users is among the assets transferred.
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. For example, if you give us an e-mail address to use the "e-mail a friend" feature of our Website, we will transmit the contents of that e-mail and your e-mail address to the recipients.
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
  * With your consent.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.
  * To enforce or apply our terms of use [INSERT AS LINK TO WEBSITE'S TERMS OF USE] and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of this company, our customers or others.

**Employment-Related Uses and Disclosures**

The following applies if you use the Website in order to apply for or inquire about working for the Company:

When you apply for a position or submit a profile to the Company, we will collect your personal information for human resources purposes. Human resources purposes may include identifying or evaluating candidates for Company positions; making a decision about whether an individual should be offered a position; maintaining appropriate record-keeping; analyzing the hiring process and outcomes; and conducting employment verification and background investigations, where permitted by law. Personal information may include, in addition to items described above in this Privacy Policy, work and education history, résumé and other relevant personal data. The Company may request certain categories of information, such as ethnicity, disability status, and veteran status, for purposes of complying, where relevant, with various government recordkeeping requirements and to undertake equal opportunities monitoring. Your provision or non-provision of such information will not affect your employment prospects. Further, you agree that your personal data may be used by us to contact you, to send you communications, or request other types of information as required or used by the Company or third parties acting on its behalf while processing your personal data for the purposes listed above. 

If you complete an online application or submit a profile, you have the option of receiving email notifications regarding positions in your selected areas of interest. If you elect to receive notifications you may change this election, or withdraw completely, at any time by updating your registration information found under My Account Options on the employment-related portion of the Website.

You agree that the information you submit for the Company’s  job application process is complete and accurate. Providing false information during any step of the application process may lead to your rejection or termination of employment. 

**Your Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information: 

  * **Tracking Technologies and Advertising.**  You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe's website. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
  * **Promotional Offers from the Company.**  If you do not wish to have your e-mail address/contact information used by the Company to promote our own or third parties' products or services, you can unsubscribe at any time by checking the relevant box located on the clicking on the unsubscribe link in any email. This opt out does not apply to information provided to the Company as a result of a product purchase, warranty registration, product service experience or other transactions.
  * **Targeted Email Advertising.**  If you do not want us to use information that we collect or that you provide to us to deliver advertisements according to our advertisers' target-audience preferences, you can unsubscribe at any time by checking the relevant box located on the clicking on the unsubscribe link in any email. 

We do not control third parties' collection or use of your information to serve interest-based advertising. However these third parties may provide you with ways to choose not to have your information collected or used in this way. You can opt out of receiving targeted ads from members of the Network Advertising Initiative (" **NAI** ") on the NAI'swebsite.

We use the following standards for marketing communications:

  * We use an unsubscribe/opt-out standard for phone, text messages, and email or for other communications like mail. You can unsubscribe at any time. Opt-out means we consider your consent is implied, but will stop the activity on your request.
  * If you contact us by email or mail, please be sure to include your full name, the types of communications you would like to receive or not receive, and your related contact information. For instance, if you would like to opt-out of mail, include your mailing address. Please allow sufficient time for your preferences to be processed. It may take up to 10 days to process your requests related to email and 4-6 weeks for other requests.
  * Please be aware that, even if you have opted out of receiving marketing communications from us, we may still contact you for transactional purposes. Some examples are contacts for customer service, product information, service or reminder notices, or recalls. We may also need to contact you with questions or information regarding your order, such as regarding order status, shipment, or refunds.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to comm@donaldson.com or writing to Donaldson Company, Corporate Communications – MS430, PO Box 1299, Minneapolis Minnesota, 55440, U.S.A.

**Do Not Track**

This Website does not monitor or identify “do not track signals” from your computer, and such signals will not impact the operation of this Website.

**Security**

While we take certain physical, electronic and administrative measures designed to protect the confidentiality of personal information, due to the nature of the Internet we cannot and do not guarantee that all such personal information will remain secure. By submitting information to us, you agree that you are aware of these risks. If you do not wish to submit your information electronically, do not do so, however in such case you may not be able to make use of the full functionality of this Website. You agree that Donaldson is not responsible for any consequence of illegal or unauthorized acts by third parties, including but not limited to hacking or similar crimes.

**Based in United States**

This Website is intended for a United States and Canadian audience.  You acknowledge, agree, and consent that any information you provide, including any personal information, will be transferred to and processed by a computer server located within the United States, and subject to United States laws and regulations. Further, if you access this Website from outside the United Stetes, you acknowledge and agree that you are responsible for compliance with any applicable local or national laws, rules or regulations applicable to such use.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page or a similar page of our Website. If we make material changes to how we treat our users' personal information, we will notify you through an additional mechanism such as through the email address we have on file for you. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active and deliverable e-mail address for you, and for periodically visiting our Website and this privacy policy to check for any changes.

**Contact Information**

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us by email at: comm@donaldson.com or writing to Donaldson Company, Inc., Corporate Communications – MS430, PO Box 1299, Minneapolis Minnesota, 55440, U.S.A.
